<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andrew Conner | startups, investing, and miscellaneous thoughts</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/</link><description>Recent content on Andrew Conner | startups, investing, and miscellaneous thoughts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright 2019 Andrew Conner</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andrewconner.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes from Creating the Perfect Pitch Deck</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/notes-from-creating-the-perfect-pitch-deck/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/notes-from-creating-the-perfect-pitch-deck/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ericbahn">Eric Bahn&lt;/a>, general partner at &lt;a href="https://www.hustlefund.vc/">Hustle Fund&lt;/a>, gave a talk about pitching investors. focusing on pre-seed/seed companies. Here's my editorialized notes of his talk&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Investment Thesis for 2020</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last year, I &lt;a href="https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2019/">outlined some investment theses for 2019&lt;/a>. With the year wrapped up, I'll quickly review how my predictions played out, and outline future investment areas I'm interested in. Writing these has helped me refine my own thoughts, and intentionally deploy capital aligned with macro views&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accreditation Laws are not Violating the American Dream</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/accreditation-laws-are-not-violating-the-american-dream/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/accreditation-laws-are-not-violating-the-american-dream/</guid><description>In light of the SEC re-evaluating accredited investor laws, Anthony Pompliano recently wrote a piece titled Accreditation Laws Are Violating The American Dream And Discriminating Against Millions. In it, he surveys how accreditation laws are keeping everyone but the already-rich from investing in startups. The argument is simple: the wealthy are capturing returns that most of America doesn't have access to and average investors are missing out. Instead, big tech companies are getting dumped on public markets after most of their appreciation has happened.</description></item><item><title>Break social media habits by removing the default feeds</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/productivity-break-habits-removing-feeds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/productivity-break-habits-removing-feeds/</guid><description>Social networks work because they form habit loops. You visit, and get a boost of dopamine, fueled by novelty. It's always new, and randomly rewards. Even if you're disappointed with what you see, it's too late. But, what if you do get value from them, and just want to be in control?
Remove social apps from your phone that have become the default filler to stillness.
Remove the default feeds with an ad blocker.
Here's my Facebook homepage:</description></item><item><title>Media Diet: More books, less news</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/media-diet-podcasts-audiobooks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/media-diet-podcasts-audiobooks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Four months ago, I took a break from the news. Partly from exhaustion. Partly because I realized how I wasn't &lt;em>informed&lt;/em>, I was &lt;em>entertained&lt;/em>. Mostly because a friend challenged me — to limit inputs and consume slower; to be intentional about information consumption. And I challenge you: I'll show you how you can learn more and avoid the outrage rollercoaster by going slower.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Request for Product: a new Calendar experience</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/a-new-calendar-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/a-new-calendar-experience/</guid><description>Google started a shift to real-time, online collaboration with their apps suite. Microsoft quickly chased. Both were primarily replicating a desktop environment on the web. This had many benefits: no forgetting to save, easier collaboration, a chance to drop unused features, better version control, and easier sharing. For many customers, this was an obvious improvement, and so the Shift to Cloud has continued.
Piece by piece, however, a new wave of products are entering the market that re-think the form factor of these productivity tools.</description></item><item><title>Coaching engineering managers for interviews</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/coaching-engineering-managers-google-interview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/coaching-engineering-managers-google-interview/</guid><description>Google recently concluded a program where senior engineering manager candidates could get coaching before interviews, in order to help experienced people be as effective as possible during their interviews. My understanding is that they had systemic problems of engineering managers performing poorly on technical interviews, so the program was created to provide pointed feedback early in the cycle.
We'll ignore what that may say about the interview process (where we provide &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; for candidates ahead of the interview), but the program is changing a bit now, and my role as a coach is ending.</description></item><item><title>On Generalists</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/on-generalists/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/on-generalists/</guid><description>Over the past couple years, I've had the fortune to coach engineers through their career journeys, including people currently in coding bootcamps, to startup founders, to people bored at their BigCo job. Fortune, because it's entirely as much a benefit for me, as I synthesize patterns for the first time to improve my own career and spot opportunities.
One pattern that's common, especially for new college grads who go straight into a FANG, is becoming specialists early. Certainly, being a proficient machine learning engineer right now is quite lucrative.</description></item><item><title>URL rewriting with fly.io</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/url-rewriting-fly.io/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/url-rewriting-fly.io/</guid><description>Recently, I moved this site to be a static site (via Hugo), as well as moving to .com (instead of .org, which I've owned for a lot longer). I didn't want to break previous URLs, but my new posts have entirely new paths, so a simple path-for-path 301 redirect won't work. Most importantly, I wanted the redirection to require nearly no maintenance and be near free.
To avoid running a small server, I considered serverless approaches that would handle the URL rewriting for me.</description></item><item><title>Investment Thesis for 2019</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2019/</guid><description>Here are my ideas that are guiding personal investments, as well as macro views. I've noted where I have skin in the game with current positioning, which may be useful to project my relative confidence.
You'll notice that I have an active portfolio, while I recommend that others stick to as boring-as-possible three-fund or inexpensive target-retirement portfolios. Later, I'll write about why I structure investments this way, but it very well may be a &amp;ldquo;do as I say, not as I do&amp;rdquo; position.</description></item><item><title>Essential Slick review</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/essential-slick-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/essential-slick-review/</guid><description>Essential Slick by Jonathan Ferguson and Richard Dallaway was recently updated to include Slick 3, which was a big update from Slick 2. Slick is a “functional relational mapping” library for Scala. Instead of focusing on Table ↔ Object relations, Slick uses functional programming concepts to build queries, bind data, and stream results. In Slick 3, the preferred API treats queries and IO operations (called DBIO) as values, which can be modified and stored without the presence of a database. This is familiar to anyone who has used scalaz's Task or Haskell's IO.</description></item><item><title>Slack Hide Typing</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/slack-hide-typing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/slack-hide-typing/</guid><description>&lt;p>I've written a very simple Chrome extension that prevents the Slack site from sending typing indications while you’re typing. My primary use case is so that I can type longer messages and use the text as a scratch pad without making others think that a message is incoming immediately.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving fast and staying secure</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/moving-fast-staying-secure/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/moving-fast-staying-secure/</guid><description>Startups often “move fast and break things” to get to market faster and test assumptions. However, they also often do not take security seriously enough. I've responsibly disclosed web vulnerabilities in sites such as Pinterest, Amazon, IMDB, and many more smaller startups. Typically, the issues were very simple and avoidable by having a culture of security. Recently, I was sent a link of a site that broke many of the guidelines below. Within three minutes, I had their database credentials. The site had many flaws, but I never even had to mangle query parameters.</description></item><item><title>Gambler's Verity?</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/gamblers-verity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/gamblers-verity/</guid><description>Flip a fair coin four times. Consider the cases, if any, after a heads. Since you're flipping a fair coin—you reason—you should notice no significant patterns in the flips after a heads, because flips are independent. However, you have heard of “hot streaks” or how random events become “due”, so you record your results.
You flip H T H H, and record “tails” and “heads” (bolded the flips after a heads). You flip T T H T and record “tails” from the 4th position.</description></item><item><title>Using Java Futures in Scala</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/using-java-future-in-scala/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/using-java-future-in-scala/</guid><description>&lt;p>Occasionally, you may need to interface with Java &lt;code>Future&lt;/code>s in Scala. Unfortunately, it is “&lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/11529145/how-do-i-wrap-a-java-util-concurrent-future-in-an-akka-future">an abomination&lt;/a>”. Several older Java libraries, like Amazon's SDK, provides asynchronous interfaces using Java's &lt;code>Future&lt;/code>s. &lt;code>java.util.concurrent.Future&lt;/code> only provides a &lt;code>.get&lt;/code>, and no mechanism to react to completion. The best solution to avoid blocking a thread checking for completion (or simply &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/17215421/scala-concurrent-future-wrapper-for-java-util-concurrent-future">&lt;code>.get&lt;/code>ing inside another thread&lt;/a>) is to periodically check for completion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scalaz Task ↔ Scala Future</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/scalaz-task-scala-future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/scalaz-task-scala-future/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since many asynchronous APIs in Scala use &lt;code>Future&lt;/code>s, if you prefer using &lt;code>Task&lt;/code>, you'll need to convert between the two. Here are two simple classes that enhance &lt;code>scalaz.concurrent.Task&lt;/code> and &lt;code>scala.concurrent.Future&lt;/code>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Useful Scala Snippets</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/useful-scala-snippets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/useful-scala-snippets/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here's a few classes and functions I've collected over the past few years that I find incredibly useful with day-to-day Scala development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dialogue above debate</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/dialogue-above-debate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/dialogue-above-debate/</guid><description>&lt;p>I'm drawn to people who engage in direct dialogue about the fundamental concepts behind complex and polarizing issues. Recently I've been listening to podcast episodes about this — individuals who are a member of a “side”, and yet are drawn away from debate and instead deeply explore what the “other side” believes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are a few that I've especially enjoyed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reactive Web Development with Play! on Java 8</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/reactive-web-development-play-java-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/reactive-web-development-play-java-8/</guid><description>James Roper, tech lead of Play! at Typesafe, spoke at Box in Mountain View, CA on 4/24/2014.
Code from the Java 8 project Play! Framework Meetup Group
Java 8 heralds a new era of reactive programming, with lambdas and promises taking the limelight as the bright new features of the language. To best take advantage of these features, Play Framework offers a ground up asynchronous full stack web framework, with a high velocity development environment, making it the most natural web framework to use with Java 8.</description></item><item><title>Habits</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/habits/</guid><description>One of the most influential books I've read is The Power of Habit, by Charles Duhigg. He explores how habits work, and how we build (and change) them.
A habit I built shortly after reading this book was reading every morning before I left for work, for at least 20 minutes. I'm a utilitarian reader — there's many other things I'd do for pleasure — so primarily read out of a love of learning. 20 minutes is short enough that I don't miss sleep, and long enough to make progress every day.</description></item><item><title>Launching Kifi</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/launching-kifi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/launching-kifi/</guid><description>After over a year of hard work, my colleagues and friends have been working on a product that — we hope! — will revolutionize searching, bookmarks, and discovery.
Briefly, it means you never have to organize your bookmarks again. Search Google, and relevant links show up on the top. To organize your links make it work well, FortyTwo has built a brilliant team of search experts who are creating the future of search.
It's been an amazing year with a fantastic team.</description></item><item><title>Education</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/ongoing/educated-a-memoir/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/ongoing/educated-a-memoir/</guid><description>Well-written, pacing of a triller, telling the nuts story of an unusual upbringing. Don't fully understand the hype, though we've had several Hillbilly to Well-Read Success stories capture our imagination in recent years (such as Hillbilly Elegy).</description></item><item><title>Our Mathematical Universe</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/our-mathematical-universe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/our-mathematical-universe/</guid><description>Max Tegmark has an unusual idea: reality is just a mathematical structure. This is a bold claim about reality, so to get those of us there, he walks through a journey of what we know about our universe and how we know it. More importantly, he builds to focus on what the same mathematical underpinnings we use in our universe predict about things we can't directly observe.
To get anywhere close to explaining his ultimate theory, he spends sufficient time explaining the cosmos, with successes and failures of previous theories, so even a non-academic can understand where multiverses came about.</description></item><item><title>Secrets of Sand Hill Road</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/secrets-of-sand-hill-road/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/secrets-of-sand-hill-road/</guid><description>Confession: I held off reading this one for several months because of the title. I assumed it was some sort of exposé on VC, or perhaps &amp;ldquo;history of A18Z&amp;rdquo;. I was entirely wrong: this book provides the background, incentives, and purpose of venture capital and starting a VC-funded company. It covers everything from governance, term sheets, equity splits, board member duties (and legal obligations), and a lot more.
The chapter on Term Sheets is worth the book alone. Despite living a short drive from Sand Hill for the past 7 years, I've never seen something written that's so clear.</description></item><item><title>Dealt</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/dealt-richard-turner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/dealt-richard-turner/</guid><description>Richard Turner is one of the most brilliant card mechanics that has ever lived. My wife and I watched this documentary covering his fascinating life and the challenges he has faced, and loved it.
As a kid, I loved card magic. I collected special decks, pamphlets from experienced magicians, and books detailing advanced techniques. Almost 15 years ago, I watched Richard Turner's instructional DVDs Fans, Flourishes, and False Shuffles and The Cheat, and was blown away by his skills.</description></item><item><title>Why Evolution is True</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/why-evolution-is-true/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/why-evolution-is-true/</guid><description>Frankly, it's hard to find balance on many issues that directly support or reject specific world-views. Evolution is a prime example. Nearly all scientists feel there is sufficient evidence for natural selection and evolution—including in humans—as the explanation of species breadth we see today. However, only 9% of white evangelicals agree. Even more surprising, each side is highly confident in their conclusion. They have arguments supporting their view, but it seems that neither side fully understands the other.
The result is a lot of talk past each other.</description></item><item><title>Radical Markets</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/radical-markets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/radical-markets/</guid><description>If you believe that markets are the most efficient way to allocate resources, what if their breadth was extended to be far beyond how they're used today? Posner and Weyl play with this concept, and deliver proposals outside the current political axis, leaving people of nearly every political persuasion both interested and aghast.
I'll focus on the proposal they get the most attention for, regarding property ownership. They offer an economic system that would implement a wealth tax, levied on all personal property valued at whatever you publicly declare its value to be.</description></item><item><title>Stillness Is the Key</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/stillness-is-the-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/stillness-is-the-key/</guid><description>I'm a Ryan Holiday fan, have received a ton of value from other books of his, such as Trust Me I'm Lying. So, I had this one pre-ordered since it was announced. Stoicism, virtue ethics, and meditation? I'm in.
Each of us has access to more information than we could reasonably use. We tell ourselves that it's part of our job, that we have to be &amp;ldquo;on top of things,&amp;rdquo; and so we give up precious time to news reports, meetings, and other forms of feedback&amp;hellip; We must stop this.</description></item><item><title>Sapiens</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/sapiens/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/sapiens/</guid><description>Yuval Noah Harari narrates the history of human kind, starting from pre-history with many types of sapiens roaming the world, to modern days. Large popular works often make for wide targets of criticism—which you'd see about Sapiens if you looked around. There's a lot to be critical of, but for me—uneducated in much of the anthropology and sociology underpinnings—there's also a lot to take away. Frankly, many of the vocal criticisms miss the point. Harari's greatest flaw is how he narrates as if detached from what he speaks about, as an unaffiliated observer reporting facts and observations; however, he frequently mixes well-agreed history with his opinions.</description></item><item><title>How Not to Die</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/how-not-to-die/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/how-not-to-die/</guid><description>Spoiler: eat plants. I love this book, and am frustrated by it. Lots to love: Dr. Greger is motivated to help people be healthy and live longer; there's nothing else. The first part of the book looks at all the top modern killers (heart disease, high blood pressure, cancer, &amp;hellip;), and gives evidence supporting plant-based diets. It's very well cited, and he's quite intelligent. Just like when reading Keto books, there's almost this underlying conspiratorial overlay on much of the evidence.</description></item><item><title>High Growth Handbook</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/high-growth-handbook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/high-growth-handbook/</guid><description>There's plenty of writing about how to start a company, but how do you take a company from early product-market fit to hypergrowth? It turns out, not many people have done this. Leading fast growing companies is a still earned through experience, with few people having the opportunity to have done this. A lot of this knowledge has been passed on through coaching and mentorship.
This book is a reference, mostly useful when growth situations come up and you need help.</description></item><item><title>Undone</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/undone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/undone/</guid><description>It's a sci-fi, fantasy, and murder mystery animated show, rolled into one. It tackles time travel, mental illness, and reality. Go in fresh — don't read any reviews or commentary, and commit to the whole season. The whole series is less than 3 hours, and comes into its own towards the end.</description></item><item><title>The End of Average</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/the-end-of-average/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/the-end-of-average/</guid><description>Our culture optimizes for &amp;ldquo;the average&amp;rdquo;. This isn't saying we encourage everyone to be average, but we measure from the average. This breaks down when a measure is &amp;ldquo;jagged&amp;rdquo;. Consider people of different sizes, and you're tasked to sort them from smallest to biggest. Do you do it by height? Well, this would rank a 1.5m tall obese person as &amp;ldquo;smaller&amp;rdquo; than a 1.6m very thin person. By weight? This has the same problem. As it turns out, &amp;ldquo;size&amp;rdquo; is jagged.</description></item><item><title>The Personalized Diet</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/the-personalized-diet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/the-personalized-diet/</guid><description>An inspiration for Levels, but could be a lot shorter. The universal best diet doesn't exist because people respond differently to foods. The best way to find out how you respond is to measure it. Unfortunately, the end of the book, with the actual protocol, is disappointing. They recommend using a finger prick, and taking a few point measurements after meals. From my own experience wearing a continuous glucose monitor, this is far too noisy.</description></item><item><title>Deep Medicine</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/deep-medicine-how-artificial-intelligence-can-make-healthcare-human-again/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/deep-medicine-how-artificial-intelligence-can-make-healthcare-human-again/</guid><description>Another health book during my research for my new startup. It won't surprise many technologists that ML is changing healthcare. Topol introduces us to the future of medicine: how humans will work with machines to provide better healthcare. He talks about what assumptions we should be careful of when designing AI health systems, and what the future may look like. He's critical of shallow medicine, which he claims most healthcare practitioners currently offer. Instead, he sees a future where full patient context can be used to provide personalized, targeted care.</description></item><item><title>Free Will</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/free-will/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/free-will/</guid><description>I've appreciated a lot of what Sam Harris has created (such as Waking Up, and especially his meditation app of the same name), so wasn't unfamiliar with his arguments. This one's short, and is okay. His arguments are not the most intellectually rigorous, but I'm not sure that was his intention. Rather than an exploration of determinism, his goal is to show that if you look closely for &amp;ldquo;the one who thinks,&amp;rdquo; it disappears. Thoughts appear in consciousness, and the autonomy we believe we have is an illusion — in fact, the illusion isn't even there.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Gathering</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/the-art-of-gathering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/the-art-of-gathering/</guid><description>We're social beings, and wonderful things happen when we gather. Great gatherings, though, don't happen by accident. They have intentionality behind who is and isn't invited, what we gather for, how long we are together, how we conclude, and how we'll remember the time together. Parker is a virtuoso at human gatherings, and shares her wisdom on how to gather well. Read this if: you are interested in hosting others, and want your gathering to be meaningful and memorable.</description></item><item><title>Doing Justice</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/doing-justice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/doing-justice/</guid><description>Preet Bharara writes about justice: what is it, how do we protect it, why should we protect it, and how do we fail? It's both the story of his career as the federal prosecutor for the Southern District of New York, but also about the world we live in. How do we effectively deliver and fight for justice? How do our leaders affect its grasp?
&amp;ldquo;[T]he rule of law&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;due process&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;presumed innocent&amp;rdquo; seem to do service these days more as political slogans than as bedrock principles… It seems preferred these days to demonize one's opponents rather than engage them, to bludgeon critics rather than win them over.</description></item><item><title>Waking Up</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/waking-up/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/waking-up/</guid><description>This is actually the second time I tried to read this, and the first where I succeeded. Previously, I found the philosophical diatribes encouraging my mind to wander — which is ironic, given the context. This time, I enjoyed it. From first principles, what is spirituality? How do people around the world—with different and contradictory beliefs—have spiritual experiences? Where do feelings of &amp;ldquo;oneness&amp;rdquo; come from?
Harris explores spirituality building from observations that we can analyze ourselves. It isn't easy though: looking at the nature of consciousness is difficult, to say the least.</description></item><item><title>Big Magic</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/big-magic-creative-living-beyond-fear/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/big-magic-creative-living-beyond-fear/</guid><description>This book is delightful. I struggle with creativity: it hasn't previously felt accessible, and never productive. Gilbert thinks that's ridiculous.
“The universe buries strange jewels deep within us all, and then stands back to see if we can find them. The hunt to uncover those jewels — that’s creative living. The courage to go on that hunt in the first place — that’s what separates a mundane existence from a more enchanted one.”
Read this if: you want to be more creative, or don't think you can be.</description></item><item><title>Taking the Work Out of Networking</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/taking-the-work-out-of-networking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/taking-the-work-out-of-networking/</guid><description>I'm a bit torn on this one. The advice inside is likely quite useful for many people, advocating for a modern interpretation of &amp;ldquo;networking&amp;rdquo;. However, at least among people I work with, much of the advice is well-known and not surprising. Read this if: you find the concept of networking pointless or overwhelming. There are incredible benefits to building a wide, diverse network.</description></item><item><title>Make Time</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/make-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/make-time/</guid><description>This doesn't have a unified philosophy on productivity. It's a book with a ton of tactics on focusing and working more effectively. However, it's far too long, and felt like a grab-bag of all the tips and tricks the authors could come up with around productivity. Don't go on Facebook, focus on one thing, avoid the news, exercise, don't drink too much coffee, hang out with friends, etc.</description></item><item><title>Extreme Ownership</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/extreme-ownership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/extreme-ownership/</guid><description>Jocko and Leif advocate for better leadership through &amp;ldquo;extreme&amp;rdquo; ownership: taking ownership of outcomes, no matter who is directly at fault. It's a pleasant read, mixing practical &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; advice with war stories. The crux, however, could have been delivered in a blog post. You'll be a far more effective leader when you take full ownership of everything under your purview.</description></item><item><title>Being Mortal</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/being-mortal-illness-medicine-and-what-matters-in-the-end/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/being-mortal-illness-medicine-and-what-matters-in-the-end/</guid><description>Gawande considers aging and the slow process of modern death. Told alongside the story of his own father's death, he asks deep questions about mortality, end of life care, and autonomy. In an age of copious medical options, he advocates for a more holistic perspective on aging. He advocates for simple things, such as focusing on quality of life—which paradoxically often extends life, more than aggressive disease management. The book takes courage, especially if you have loved ones going through end of life care.</description></item><item><title>Thinking in Bets</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/thinking-in-bets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/thinking-in-bets/</guid><description>Annie Duke, renowned poker player, writes about applying poker thinking to life. Specifically, separating outcomes from expected value, and making choices with incomplete information. If you've played a lot of poker—or, traded in financial markets—there's not too much surprising here.
In terms of applicable value, the lesson is fairly short, and could have been a blog post. Seek contrarian opinions and evidence against your biases. Don't blame negative outcomes on bad luck or necessarily bad decision making: the outcome only has a loose connection to the quality of the decision.</description></item><item><title>The Righteous Mind</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/the-righteous-mind/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/the-righteous-mind/</guid><description>This book changed the way I thought about morals, beliefs, and communication. Presented as a philosophy of morals—such as surveying the different types of morals we see in cultures—this book craft-fully made me think about my own moral compass. What do I value? Where do I place my values?
We make decisions without critical thinking, and are masters at explaining our decisions with rationality. We have this (shared) illusion that our beliefs are based in rationality, and thus when we disagree, we hit roadblocks.</description></item><item><title>Trust Me, I'm Lying</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/trust-me-im-lying/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/media-diet/trust-me-im-lying/</guid><description>An appropriate start to my media diet. This book isn't nearly as conspiratorial as you'd think. Rather, it's a study of incentives: how are different forms of media incentivized? I deeply respect the work that good journalists do, but unfortunately, that's not what pays the bills for the news outlets. Since subscriptions are down, we're in a feedback cycle where poorly-researched, quickly-written hype pieces get more attention than actually impacting journalism. Read this if: you're curious about reducing media consumption.</description></item><item><title>Caution when using Play's TemporaryFile</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/caution-play-temporaryfile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/caution-play-temporaryfile/</guid><description>Play! Framework provides several BodyParsers out of the box to parse common HTTP request bodies. One of them is for file uploads. Since Play can't reasonably know what you're doing with the body, they can't aggressively delete the file after the result is returned. Their solution is to clean up the file when the variable is garbage collected, using Java's finalize—rarely seen in the Scala world. Since the TemporaryFile is held inside request (request.body: TemporaryFile), this is usually reasonable since request won't be GCed during the lifecycle of the request.</description></item><item><title>Scala Days 2015 Talks</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/scala-days-2015-talks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/scala-days-2015-talks/</guid><description>Scala Days 2015 talks have posted. My favorites:
Scala Records: Extensible records and type-indexed maps Toward a Safer Scala Reactive Slick for Database Programming Why Scala.js Type-safe off-heap memory for Scala Delimited dependently-typed monadic checked exceptions in Scala Scala Collections Performance</description></item></channel></rss>