<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Andrew Conner | startups, investing, and miscellaneous thoughts</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Andrew Conner | startups, investing, and miscellaneous thoughts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright 2021 Andrew Conner</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andrewconner.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Other Swans That Define Us</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/the-other-swans-that-define-us/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/the-other-swans-that-define-us/</guid><description>Imagine you logged the outcome of many casino visits where you played roulette until you were up at least $20 or lost $1500. You would naturally end up leaving ahead most of the time, and occasionally would lose a lot.
Here&amp;rsquo;s one possible outcome over 100 casino visits:
As expected, most times you win a small amount, and occasionally—3 times in this case—you lose a lot.
You want to improve your system, so try to figure out how to avoid those big losing days.</description></item><item><title>Common Digital Infrastructure</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/common-digital-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/common-digital-infrastructure/</guid><description>Governments, and thus us as upstanding Homo politicus beings, are accustomed to thinking about common infrastructure: organizations and structures that promote further wealth-building, but don&amp;rsquo;t always have a natural market-based mechanism to exist. We can think about them as &amp;ldquo;resource enablers&amp;rdquo;, providing economic benefit while being agnostic about value capture.
Not all of these are anti-market. For example, the electrical grid facilitates nearly the entire modern economy, and charges roughly the cost of production instead of value. We have a ton of these: communications networks, safety regulations, clean air/water infrastructure, sewage and sanitation systems, environmental productions, vaccination programs, financial regulatory frameworks, and the public postal system.</description></item><item><title>The Ladder Theory of Meaning</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/ladder-theory-of-meaning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/ladder-theory-of-meaning/</guid><description>I once read a book that shattered my core. It was beautiful, effectively breaking down and building up my model of the world. Without hyperbole, how I viewed my place among others changed such that many of my life perspectives before this book seem adolescent.
Naturally, I became a That Book evangelist, telling everyone I knew about how good the book was. It was long, yes, but be patient — it&amp;rsquo;ll change the way you see the world.
I won&amp;rsquo;t tell you what it was, the reception was less enthusiastic.</description></item><item><title>Making the Internet Work for You: YouTube</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/making-the-internet-work-for-you-youtube/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/making-the-internet-work-for-you-youtube/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re accustomed to social network dangers: doomscrolling, the media feedback loop, polarization, etc. Their currency is attention, and thus are naturally designed to addict by providing spaced dopamine hits.
Many social networks also have incredible value, but self-control in the moment fails. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you to control them so that you pick what you get out of them. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past several years building systems to maximize social network value, while minimizing natural feedback loops. I&amp;rsquo;ll start with YouTube, which I consider the most valuable social network to have ever existed.</description></item><item><title>“Woo” beliefs</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/woo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/woo/</guid><description>My default disposition is fairly rationalist—or at least, rationalist-informed—and have a gut distaste towards &amp;ldquo;the woo&amp;rdquo;. I also have plenty of curiosity and believe that wisdom is often lossily encoded in culture, so have tried and experienced quite a few things that I initially met with a wave of skepticism. Many have become significantly meaningful in my life.
Scientific reductionism is the modus operandi of thought in Western, educated circles. For it&amp;rsquo;s flaws, this approach has pushed the boundaries of our knowledge of how the world works, but consistently has blindspots between domains, with significant consequences.</description></item><item><title>Angel investing without investing</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/angel-investing-without-investing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/angel-investing-without-investing/</guid><description>Angel investing is—for most people—a bad investment. As such, accreditation is rarely the limiting factor to being able to realize outsized investment returns, because variance is incredibly high while median performance is tepid. However, it can have very net positive externalities that include networking opportunities, learning about venture, getting involved in exciting companies, and honing your startup skillset.
If you’re interested in angel investing, but don’t yet have a portfolio large enough to support diversified meaningful bets, there’s a few options to start down this path and capture a lot of the value you’re after.</description></item><item><title>Append List System: How to stay on top of everything</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/append-list-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/append-list-system/</guid><description>For several years, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a strategy that I use to stay on top of all my personal and work projects, while not getting overwhelmed by infinitely-growing lists. Using this strategy, I&amp;rsquo;m able to regularly surprise people about how I remembered to do some passing request they had, and am able to bring back concepts after weeks of dormancy. It&amp;rsquo;s quite simple, and adaptable to many different tools.
Guiding Principles:
When a task arises, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know the absolute priority and allocate time effectively.</description></item><item><title>Notes from Creating the Perfect Pitch Deck</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/notes-from-creating-the-perfect-pitch-deck/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/notes-from-creating-the-perfect-pitch-deck/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ericbahn">Eric Bahn&lt;/a>, general partner at &lt;a href="https://www.hustlefund.vc/">Hustle Fund&lt;/a>, gave a talk about pitching investors, focusing on pre-seed/seed companies. Here&amp;rsquo;s my editorialized notes of his talk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Investment Thesis for 2020</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last year, I &lt;a href="https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2019/">outlined some investment theses for 2019&lt;/a>. With the year wrapped up, I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly review how my predictions played out, and outline future investment areas I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. Writing these has helped me refine my own thoughts, and intentionally deploy capital aligned with macro views.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accreditation Laws are not Violating the American Dream</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/accreditation-laws-are-not-violating-the-american-dream/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/accreditation-laws-are-not-violating-the-american-dream/</guid><description>In light of the SEC re-evaluating accredited investor laws, Anthony Pompliano recently wrote a piece titled Accreditation Laws Are Violating The American Dream And Discriminating Against Millions. In it, he surveys how accreditation laws are keeping everyone but the already-rich from investing in startups. The argument is simple: the wealthy are capturing returns that most of America doesn&amp;rsquo;t have access to and average investors are missing out. Instead, big tech companies are getting dumped on public markets after most of their appreciation has happened.</description></item><item><title>Break social media habits by removing the default feeds</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/productivity-break-habits-removing-feeds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/productivity-break-habits-removing-feeds/</guid><description>Social networks work because they form habit loops. You visit, and get a boost of dopamine, fueled by novelty. It&amp;rsquo;s always new, and randomly rewards. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re disappointed with what you see, it&amp;rsquo;s too late. But, what if you do get value from them, and just want to be in control?
Remove social apps from your phone that have become the default filler to stillness.
Remove the default feeds with an ad blocker.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my Facebook homepage:</description></item><item><title>Media Diet: More books, less news</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/media-diet-podcasts-audiobooks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/media-diet-podcasts-audiobooks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Four months ago, I took a break from the news. Partly from exhaustion. Partly because I realized how I wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>informed&lt;/em>, I was &lt;em>entertained&lt;/em>. Mostly because a friend challenged me — to limit inputs and consume slower; to be intentional about information consumption. And I challenge you: I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can learn more and avoid the outrage rollercoaster by going slower.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Request for Product: a new Calendar experience</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/a-new-calendar-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/a-new-calendar-experience/</guid><description>Google started a shift to real-time, online collaboration with their apps suite. Microsoft quickly chased. Both were primarily replicating a desktop environment on the web. This had many benefits: no forgetting to save, easier collaboration, a chance to drop unused features, better version control, and easier sharing. For many customers, this was an obvious improvement, and so the Shift to Cloud has continued.
Piece by piece, however, a new wave of products are entering the market that re-think the form factor of these productivity tools.</description></item><item><title>Coaching engineering managers for interviews</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/coaching-engineering-managers-google-interview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/coaching-engineering-managers-google-interview/</guid><description>Google recently concluded a program where senior engineering manager candidates could get coaching before interviews, in order to help experienced people be as effective as possible during their interviews. My understanding is that they had systemic problems of engineering managers performing poorly on technical interviews, so the program was created to provide pointed feedback early in the cycle.
We&amp;rsquo;ll ignore what that may say about the interview process (where we provide &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; for candidates ahead of the interview), but the program is changing a bit now, and my role as a coach is ending.</description></item><item><title>On Generalists</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/on-generalists/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/on-generalists/</guid><description>Over the past couple years, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the fortune to coach engineers through their career journeys, including people currently in coding bootcamps, to startup founders, to people bored at their BigCo job. Fortune, because it&amp;rsquo;s entirely as much a benefit for me, as I synthesize patterns for the first time to improve my own career and spot opportunities.
One pattern that&amp;rsquo;s common, especially for new college grads who go straight into a FANG, is becoming specialists early. Certainly, being a proficient machine learning engineer right now is quite lucrative.</description></item><item><title>Investment Thesis for 2019</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/investment-thesis-2019/</guid><description>Here are my ideas that are guiding personal investments, as well as macro views. I&amp;rsquo;ve noted where I have skin in the game with current positioning, which may be useful to project my relative confidence.
You&amp;rsquo;ll notice that I have an active portfolio, while I recommend that others stick to as boring-as-possible three-fund or inexpensive target-retirement portfolios. Later, I&amp;rsquo;ll write about why I structure investments this way, but it very well may be a &amp;ldquo;do as I say, not as I do&amp;rdquo; position.</description></item><item><title>Adventures in Security and Hacking</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/adventures-in-security-and-hacking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/adventures-in-security-and-hacking/</guid><description>Information security has fascinated me as a hobby. Finding web vulnerabilities is a game of (ab)using a system in a permitted but unintended way. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the more fun things I have discovered. All were all responsibly disclosed to the vendor and fixed, and outside of established bug bounty programs, I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend poking around into other people&amp;rsquo;s systems.
XSS on thousands of domains, courtesy of unsubscribe links One obvious place to look for vulnerabilities are in URLs. You see a ?</description></item><item><title>Slack Hide Typing</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/slack-hide-typing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/slack-hide-typing/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a very simple Chrome extension that prevents the Slack site from sending typing indications while you’re typing. My primary use case is so that I can type longer messages and use the text as a scratch pad without making others think that a message is incoming immediately.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving fast and staying secure</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/moving-fast-staying-secure/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/moving-fast-staying-secure/</guid><description>Startups often “move fast and break things” to get to market faster and test assumptions. However, they also often do not take security seriously enough. I&amp;rsquo;ve responsibly disclosed web vulnerabilities in sites such as Pinterest, Amazon, IMDB, and many more smaller startups. Typically, the issues were very simple and avoidable by having a culture of security. Recently, I was sent a link of a site that broke many of the guidelines below. Within three minutes, I had their database credentials. The site had many flaws, but I never even had to mangle query parameters.</description></item><item><title>Gambler's Verity?</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/gamblers-verity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/gamblers-verity/</guid><description>Flip a fair coin four times. Consider the cases, if any, after a heads. Since you&amp;rsquo;re flipping a fair coin—you reason—you should notice no significant patterns in the flips after a heads, because flips are independent. However, you have heard of “hot streaks” or how random events become “due”, so you record your results.
You flip H T H H, and record “tails” and “heads” (bolded the flips after a heads). You flip T T H T and record “tails” from the 4th position.</description></item><item><title>Dialogue above debate</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/dialogue-above-debate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/dialogue-above-debate/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m drawn to people who engage in direct dialogue about the fundamental concepts behind complex and polarizing issues. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to podcast episodes about this — individuals who are a member of a “side”, and yet are drawn away from debate and instead deeply explore what the “other side” believes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are a few that I&amp;rsquo;ve especially enjoyed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Habits</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/habits/</guid><description>One of the most influential books I&amp;rsquo;ve read is The Power of Habit, by Charles Duhigg. He explores how habits work, and how we build (and change) them.
A habit I built shortly after reading this book was reading every morning before I left for work, for at least 20 minutes. I&amp;rsquo;m a utilitarian reader — there&amp;rsquo;s many other things I&amp;rsquo;d do for pleasure — so primarily read out of a love of learning. 20 minutes is short enough that I don&amp;rsquo;t miss sleep, and long enough to make progress every day.</description></item><item><title>Launching Kifi</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/launching-kifi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/launching-kifi/</guid><description>After over a year of hard work, my colleagues and friends have been working on a product that — we hope! — will revolutionize searching, bookmarks, and discovery.
Briefly, it means you never have to organize your bookmarks again. Search Google, and relevant links show up on the top. To organize your links make it work well, FortyTwo has built a brilliant team of search experts who are creating the future of search.
It&amp;rsquo;s been an amazing year with a fantastic team.</description></item><item><title>URL rewriting with fly.io</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/url-rewriting-fly.io/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/url-rewriting-fly.io/</guid><description>Recently, I moved this site to be a static site (via Hugo), as well as moving to .com (instead of .org, which I&amp;rsquo;ve owned for a lot longer). I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to break previous URLs, but my new posts have entirely new paths, so a simple path-for-path 301 redirect won&amp;rsquo;t work. Most importantly, I wanted the redirection to require nearly no maintenance and be near free.
To avoid running a small server, I considered serverless approaches that would handle the URL rewriting for me.</description></item><item><title>Essential Slick review</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/essential-slick-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/essential-slick-review/</guid><description>Essential Slick by Jonathan Ferguson and Richard Dallaway was recently updated to include Slick 3, which was a big update from Slick 2. Slick is a “functional relational mapping” library for Scala. Instead of focusing on Table ↔ Object relations, Slick uses functional programming concepts to build queries, bind data, and stream results. In Slick 3, the preferred API treats queries and IO operations (called DBIO) as values, which can be modified and stored without the presence of a database. This is familiar to anyone who has used scalaz&amp;rsquo;s Task or Haskell&amp;rsquo;s IO.</description></item><item><title>Using Java Futures in Scala</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/using-java-future-in-scala/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/using-java-future-in-scala/</guid><description>&lt;p>Occasionally, you may need to interface with Java &lt;code>Future&lt;/code>s in Scala. Unfortunately, it is “&lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/11529145/how-do-i-wrap-a-java-util-concurrent-future-in-an-akka-future">an abomination&lt;/a>”. Several older Java libraries, like Amazon&amp;rsquo;s SDK, provides asynchronous interfaces using Java&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>Future&lt;/code>s. &lt;code>java.util.concurrent.Future&lt;/code> only provides a &lt;code>.get&lt;/code>, and no mechanism to react to completion. The best solution to avoid blocking a thread checking for completion (or simply &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/17215421/scala-concurrent-future-wrapper-for-java-util-concurrent-future">&lt;code>.get&lt;/code>ing inside another thread&lt;/a>) is to periodically check for completion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scalaz Task ↔ Scala Future</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/scalaz-task-scala-future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/scalaz-task-scala-future/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since many asynchronous APIs in Scala use &lt;code>Future&lt;/code>s, if you prefer using &lt;code>Task&lt;/code>, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to convert between the two. Here are two simple classes that enhance &lt;code>scalaz.concurrent.Task&lt;/code> and &lt;code>scala.concurrent.Future&lt;/code>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caution when using Play's TemporaryFile</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/caution-play-temporaryfile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/caution-play-temporaryfile/</guid><description>Play! Framework provides several BodyParsers out of the box to parse common HTTP request bodies. One of them is for file uploads. Since Play can&amp;rsquo;t reasonably know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing with the body, they can&amp;rsquo;t aggressively delete the file after the result is returned. Their solution is to clean up the file when the variable is garbage collected, using Java&amp;rsquo;s finalize—rarely seen in the Scala world. Since the TemporaryFile is held inside request (request.body: TemporaryFile), this is usually reasonable since request won&amp;rsquo;t be GCed during the lifecycle of the request.</description></item><item><title>Scala Days 2015 Talks</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/scala-days-2015-talks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/scala-days-2015-talks/</guid><description>Scala Days 2015 talks have posted. My favorites:
Scala Records: Extensible records and type-indexed maps Toward a Safer Scala Reactive Slick for Database Programming Why Scala.js Type-safe off-heap memory for Scala Delimited dependently-typed monadic checked exceptions in Scala Scala Collections Performance</description></item><item><title>Useful Scala Snippets</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/useful-scala-snippets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/useful-scala-snippets/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a few classes and functions I&amp;rsquo;ve collected over the past few years that I find incredibly useful with day-to-day Scala development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reactive Web Development with Play! on Java 8</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/reactive-web-development-play-java-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/reactive-web-development-play-java-8/</guid><description>James Roper, tech lead of Play! at Typesafe, spoke at Box in Mountain View, CA on 4/24/2014.
Code from the Java 8 project Play! Framework Meetup Group
Java 8 heralds a new era of reactive programming, with lambdas and promises taking the limelight as the bright new features of the language. To best take advantage of these features, Play Framework offers a ground up asynchronous full stack web framework, with a high velocity development environment, making it the most natural web framework to use with Java 8.</description></item><item><title>Durango, Colorado</title><link>https://andrewconner.com/posts/durango/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewconner.com/posts/durango/</guid><description>After living in the Bay Area for 8 years, in January 2021 my wife and I (and dog!) moved to Durango, Colorado. We had road tripped through previously, and loved the pace of life, access to outdoors, fitness culture, and walkability. It&amp;rsquo;s a small mountain town that has avoided stains of suburbia. We walk to the grocery store, and have easy access to mountain biking, river sports, rock climbing, hiking, skiing, and more. We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled with our decision.
if (!</description></item></channel></rss>